bart.gov 2019-12-22

# Privacy Policy | bart.gov

For the Official BART App Terms of Service and Privacy Policy visit: <https://www.bart.gov/siteinfo/bart-app-privacy>

 **Privacy Policy Key Points**

  * BART collects data from User’s use of BART’s online services and programs.
  * If User uses BART’s online services and programs, BART may use User’s Personally Identifiable Information to better administer these programs and services.
  * BART safeguards User’s Personally Identifiable Information and uses it for legitimate purposes.
  * User’s use of BART’s websites, programs, and services constitutes acceptance of the terms of this Privacy Policy. 

 **Privacy at bart.gov**  
Because BART receives certain types of information from Users of online services and programs, BART wants Users to understand the terms and conditions regarding the use of that information. The following privacy statement discloses what information BART receives and how BART uses it.

 **What type of information does BART receive?**  
The information BART receives depends upon what User does when using online services and programs. In general, BART receives two types of information: The personal information User provides voluntarily, and aggregated information about users as a whole.

 **Personal Information**  
BART may request personal information, e.g. when User registers as a vendor, submits comments, enters a contest, subscribes to an email list, or plans a BART trip using User’s address or location. This personal information may include, but is not limited to, User’s name, email address, phone number, street address, or User’s location. If User uses BART's online employment application, BART may request other types of personal information required to process User’s application.

 **Aggregated Information**  
BART receives certain types of aggregated information about general activity at BART websites. This information does not include personal information, but does include how many times a BART website has been visited, which pages or search terms are most frequently requested or queried, what domain name visitors are coming from and the date and time of each visit.

 **How is this information used?**  
The personal information User voluntarily provides is used to fulfill User’s request, e.g. reply to User’s comments or enter User in a contest, subscribe User to an email list, or planning a BART trip using User’s address or location. BART does not share, sell, trade, or rent personal information to anyone, or disclose that information except: 1) when the purpose and manner of the disclosure has been disclosed to User prior to User providing the information, or 2) when disclosure is required by law.

The aggregated information BART receives is compiled for statistical analysis and reporting. It helps BART build a better online services and programs for Users. For example, it helps BART determine areas of a BART website that Users like and don't like based on traffic to those areas or peak traffic hours. BART may share aggregated information with third parties and include it in public records (see Public Records below).

  * BART may use a third party Digital Subscription Management (DSM) service called GovDelivery. When using it, User may voluntarily provide certain information, some of which may identify User personally, such as User’s name or email address. GovDelivery does not share information gathered through BART with third parties for promotional purposes. To find out more about GovDelivery, their technology, their privacy policy and other information visit the [GovDelivery Privacy Overview](https://www.govdelivery.com/legal-privacy/).
  * BART may use a third party Digital Subscription Management (DSM) service called MailChimp. When using it, User may voluntarily provide certain information, some of which may identify User personally, such as User’s name or email address. MailChimp does not share information gathered through BART with third parties for promotional purposes. To find out more about MailChimp, their technology, their privacy policy and other information visit the [MailChimp Privacy Overview](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/ "External Links").
  * BART may use third party traffic measurement service called Google Analytics to gather and compile website usage information. Google Analytics may collect User’s IP address and the page URL that User is visiting. It may set a cookie that will enable it to function properly. To find out more about Google Analytics, their technology, their privacy policy and their opt-out alternatives visit the [Google Analytics Privacy Overview](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/).
  * BART may use Urchin tracking module (UTM) codes to track performance of links from BART websites and social media channels. A UTM code is a snippet of text that helps BART identify where website traffic comes from and track performance of marketing activities. The information from UTM codes appears in BART’s analytics reports, including Google Analytics.
  * BART may use third-party re-marketing tracking cookies, including Facebook Conversion Tracking Pixel and Google AdWords, to deliver BART-related advertisements. This use of cookies means we will show ads to you on other websites besides BART. Facebook Conversion Tracking Pixel follows the actions of users after they are redirected to BART websites by clicking on a Facebook advertisement. We do not collect any identifiable information through the use of these third party re-marketing systems.
  * BART may use third party marketing tools, including Facebook Custom Audiences, to display advertisements to website visitors on Facebook, based upon email addresses provided by users to BART. BART may also use information based on follower’s social media accounts, such as demographic and other information about an individual’s lifestyle, to improve marketing efforts to deliver BART-related information.

 **IP Addresses**  
An Internet Protocol (IP) address is a unique string of numbers that is assigned to a User’s computer by User’s Internet service provider. This number is logged automatically by BART’s servers whenever User visits a site along with the time of User’s visit and the pages User has visited. Logging IP addresses is a standard practice on the Internet and is done automatically by most sites. BART uses IP addresses to help diagnose and fix server and application problems and otherwise administer the site.

 **Geolocation**  
BART may use Global Positioning System (GPS) technology (or other similar technology) to determine User’s current location in order to assist User in planning a BART trip.  BART will not share User’s location with any other party.

 **Public Records**  
As a governmental agency, BART is governed by the California Public Records Act. (California Government Code section 6250 et seq.) As such, most business conducted and communications exchanged with BART may become a public record and subject to public inspection.  BART will, to the extent permitted by law, protect information exempt from disclosure under the California Public Records Act, including private, confidential, and proprietary information (confidential information).  User agrees to hold BART harmless and, at BART’s option, provide legal defense for BART from all claims and demands including attorneys’ fees asserted against BART that may result from BART refusing to make public documents that User has designated as confidential information.  User also agrees that, if any action is filed in court seeking disclosure of such confidential information, BART may deposit the documents with the court and User will defend its designation of the information as confidential.

 **Sending E-Mail**  
If User sends e-mail to BART that includes personal information, BART normally will use the information only to respond to User’s message. However, BART may forward User’s e-mail to another agency or entity if BART believes that such agency or entity is better prepared to respond to User’s question. BART does not give or sell e-mail information to others for commercial purposes. If User sends BART a threat or a message that describes or promotes unlawful activity, BART will forward the e-mail to the appropriate law enforcement authorities.

 **Links to Other Sites**  
BART may provide links to web pages that are not a BART-managed website. The Privacy Policy described herein does not necessarily apply to those sites. BART suggests that site visitors contact these sites directly for information on their data collection and privacy policies.

 **Site Security and Monitoring**  
BART monitors network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or to otherwise cause damage to BART websites. Anyone using BART’s online services and programs expressly consents to such monitoring.

 **Cookies**  
A cookie is a small data file that websites commonly write to User’s hard drive when User visits a website. A cookie file contains information that can identify User anonymously in order to track traffic patterns and add functionality to the website. The cookies on BART websites do not identify User personally but rather identify User’s computer when User visits BART websites. A cookie cannot read data off User’s hard disk or read cookie files created by other websites. User’s browser can be set to warn User before accepting cookies and may choose to refuse cookies by turning them off in User’s browser. User does not need to have cookies turned on to use the majority of BART websites, but User will need to allow cookies in certain areas in order to perform certain functions. BART websites allows users to clear cookies.

 **Updates**  
If BART updates its Privacy Policy, BART will update this page so that Users are always aware of what information is collected, how it is used and under what circumstances it is disclosed.  BART reserves the right to update this privacy policy at any time. This page was last updated on November 13, 2019.

 **Consent**  
By using BART websites, User consents to the collection and use of information and monitoring, as described above.
